A Guide to the Letters Received by Dolley Madison, 1795-1812 and n.d.
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Letters Received by Dolley Madison 1795-1812 and n.d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5834
This collection consists of 11 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased on 1958 April 11.
Scope and Content Information
The letters concern Thomas Paine, spring fever in Virginia, James Madison, and personal news.
Contents List
- Rob. Hon[yman] to Dolley Madison, concerns effect of Thomas Paine's book on the peoples' minds and his Natural Theology; and the law subjecting lands to payments of debts, before the assembly 1795 Jan 25, ALS. 3 p.
- Barry Grove to Dolley Madison, concerns "Spring Fever" in Virginia; the dancing, frolicking, courting, and marriage of young men and women 1798 April 8, ALS. 4 p.
- Rob. Honyman to Dolley Madison, expresses high esteem for Mr. Madison 1799 July 19, ALS. 1 p.
- R. H. Hay to Dolley Madison, expresses hope that Miss Pain[sic] will bestow some attention upon Mr. B[urwell]1802 Dec 8., ALS. 2 p.
- John Goulding to Dolley Madison, expresses joy and offers congratulations on one of the President's proclamations 1809 Apr 20, ALS. 1 p.
- John Goulding to Dolley Madison, desires his petition to be held secondary to those of persons with families 1809 Oct 4, ALS. 1 p.
- Sir Augustus John Foster to Dolley Madison, declines invitation to [sleighing] party 1812 Jan 24, ALS. 1 p.
- Maria (Martin) Keene to Dolley Madison, letter of introduction for Mrs. Benaudebt, a Roman Catholic whose work is devoted to help the poor, sick, aged, and infirm n. Feb. 28 ("Saturday"), ALS. 1 p.
- A. M. Mason [?Mrs. Genl. (sic)] to Dolley Madison, concerns barrel of oranges bruised from carting n.d., ALS. 1 p.
- Lucy Lyons Hopkins to Dolley Madison, declines invitation n.d., ALS. 1 p.
- E.K. Hay to Dolley Madison, concerns purchase of accessories n.d., ALS. 1 p.